<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Indra Bishnoi</title>
    <link>https://ibishnoi.github.io//</link>
    <description>Recent content on Indra Bishnoi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 21:49:20 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ibishnoi.github.io//index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Data Importation in R</title>
      <link>https://ibishnoi.github.io//blog/2020/10/02/import/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 21:49:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ibishnoi.github.io//blog/2020/10/02/import/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial, I will teach you how to import your data into R from a multitude of sources. Importing your data correctly can help you prevent several time consuming mistakes in the future. Before you begin, remember to put your file into your working directory.
For importation, you will need to install the following packages, respectively.
install.packages(&amp;quot;tidyverse&amp;quot;) install.packages(&amp;quot;readxl&amp;quot;) install.packages(&amp;quot;foreign&amp;quot;)  After you&amp;rsquo;ve downloaded the necessary package, you&amp;rsquo;re ready to import your data!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Management in R</title>
      <link>https://ibishnoi.github.io//blog/2020/10/02/management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 21:49:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ibishnoi.github.io//blog/2020/10/02/management/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial, I will teach you how to manage your data in R. Specifically, how to view and select your data, and how to deal with missing data.
Before you begin, remember to import your data.
Viewing your data If your data frame is called df, then use the &amp;lt;str()&amp;gt; function to view it&amp;rsquo;s structure.
str(df)  To view the first six lines of df use the function &amp;lt;head()&amp;gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PWR in R</title>
      <link>https://ibishnoi.github.io//blog/2020/10/02/pwr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 21:49:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ibishnoi.github.io//blog/2020/10/02/pwr/</guid>
      <description>As researchers it’s always tough to gage how many participants we need to recruit for our study. There are a number of ways to figure this out, but R offers some good packages that do this for us.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the pwr package. To begin, let&amp;rsquo;s install and call on this package:
install.packages(&amp;quot;pwr&amp;quot;) library(pwr)  Once you&amp;rsquo;ve got that, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the many statistical analyses this package supports.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks and Conferences</title>
      <link>https://ibishnoi.github.io//blog/2020/10/02/talksandconferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 21:49:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ibishnoi.github.io//blog/2020/10/02/talksandconferences/</guid>
      <description>Developmental Disabilities Research Day In May of 2018, I was given the opportunity to give an oral presentation for Developmental Disabilities Research Day at Western University.
This was the first oral presentation I had ever done and it was right at the start of my MSc! When I first heard that I was selected for an oral presentation for this event, I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel prepared at all. However, a lab mate at the time gave me the confidence I needed (and helped me practice of course)!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://ibishnoi.github.io//about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ibishnoi.github.io//about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Indra Bishnoi. I am a neuroscience doctoral student working at the interface between cancer research, immunology, and behavioural neuroscience.
Co-supervised in the lab of Dr. Klaus-Peter Ossenkopp and Dr. Martin Kavaliers at the University of Western Ontario, my research is currently funded by the Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council of Canada (NSERC) Canada Graduate Scholarships - Doctoral Program. I focus on the development of a model of anticipatory nausea based on conditioned disgust behaviors and the influence of immune activation and microbiome metabolites on behavioural development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://ibishnoi.github.io//contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ibishnoi.github.io//contact/</guid>
      <description>Have any questions?  Please feel free to contact me through email, LinkedIn, or Facebook. You can find more information on my publications on my Google Scholars.
 ibishnoi@uwo.ca
https://www.linkedin.com/in/indrabishnoi/
https://www.facebook.com/indra.r.bishnoi/
https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=5WyfFmwAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum vitae</title>
      <link>https://ibishnoi.github.io//cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ibishnoi.github.io//cv/</guid>
      <description>Education Ph.D. in Neuroscience, Western University (2018-)
B.A. Honors Double Major in Psychology and Sociology, Western University (2013-2018)
Scholarships, Awards, &amp;amp; Honors Canada Graduate Scholarship-Doctoral Program: NSERC ($105,000, 2020 - 23)
Science Rendezvous Innovation Showcase: “Jack of All Trades: Indra Bishnoi” (2020)
Ontario Graduate Scholarship ($15,000, Declined, 2019/2020)
Canada Graduate Scholarship-Master’s Program: NSERC ($17,500, 2019)
Neuroscience Conference Travel Award ($500, 2019)
Dean’s Honor List: Western University (2017-2018)
Social Science Alumni Award: Western University ($1,500, 2017)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
